

Himanshu Kumar

Operations Associate (Solution Delivery) at Maximl

Phone: 7077100486

Address: At Chakfatah, Post-Kajri Buzurg, Police Station-Jandaha,

District- Vaishali, Hajipur, Bihar- 844507

Website: https://www.linkedin.com/in/himanshu-kumar-ee/

Email: himanshukumar.ee@gmail.com

Himanshu Kumar is currently working with Maximl Labs Pvt Ltd. He has industrial experience in Project Management, Team Management, Operations, and Technical Services.

He is skilled in Microsoft Office, Internet of Things (Arduino UNO), and Electrical Power Systems. He is appreciated by his colleagues for meeting deadlines, Team management, accurate research, and effective problem-solving.

EXPERIENCE

Maximl Labs Pvt Ltd

April 2022 to Present

Operations Associate (Solution Delivery)

- To Provide Digital solutions in Oil Refineries for Real-Time Shutdown Monitoring
- To Manage Onsite Team along with Client interactions.
- To manage Company's Assets and resources.

Maximl Labs Pvt Ltd

March 2021 to March 2022

Operations Executive

Roles and Responsibilities:

• To Provide Digital solutions in Oil Refineries for Real-Time Shutdown Monitoring

KernelSphere Technologies Pvt Ltd

December 2018 to March 2020

IOT Trainer

Roles and Responsibilities:

- To Give Training about IOT and its Practical Applications to College Students.
- To develop IOT Based Smart Devices.

Mallak Specialties Pvt Ltd

July 2018 to October 2018

Management Trainee Electrical Engineer

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Maintenance of existing Electrical Systems.
- Planning, Design and Installation of new Electrical Systems.

EDUCATION

KIIT Deemed to be University, Bhubaneswar, Odisha

July 2014 to June 2018

B.Tech (Electrical Engineering)

Marks-8.15 CGPA out of 10

RR Intermediate College, Lakhanpur- Khoksa, Vaishali, Bihar

July 2011 to June 2013

Class 12th (Science)

Marks- 68.4%

Class 10th

- Marks- 65.4%
- Scored highest marks in Mathematics in School

SKILLS

- MS Office
- Internet of Things
- Arduino UNO and MEGA
- Electrical Power System
- Team Management

LANGUAGES

English (Full Professional Proficiency including Read, Write and Speak), **Hindi** (Full Professional Proficiency including Read, Write and Speak)

PROJECT

Scopes of Biomas Production in Agricultural belt of Odisha

November 2017 to April 2018

Feasibility analysis of a Biomass based 5 MW Power Plant in the district of Ganjam, Odisha

INDUSTRIAL TRAININGS Internet of Things KernelSphere Technologies Pvt Ltd	01/06/2018 to 30/06/2018
Solar PV Design, Installation, Operation and Maintenance. JS Renewable in association with KIIT Deemed to be University	26/02/2018 to 29/04/2018
Electrical Power Transmission and Distribution system OPTCL, Chandaka, Bhubaneswar, Odisha	11/05/2017 to 13/06/2017
Industrial Automation using PLC CTTC, Infocity, Bhubaneswar, Odisha	01/12/2016 to 30/12/2016
Thermal power generation NTPC Limited., Barh, Patna, Bihar	02/05/2016 to 30/05/2016

VOLUNTEERING

National Service Scheme (NSS)

July 2015 to June 2018

Student Coordinator

- Organised and attended Multiple Tree Plantation drive in Bhubaneswar.
- Visited Tribal villages of Odisha for educating children along with their parents.
- Got certified by Ministry of Youth Affairs and Sports, Government of India.